Youngjin Ko

Youngjin Ko

Yongin, South Korea

+82 10-4577-3524

youngjin.ko@youngjinko.me

https://www.linkedin.com/in/youngjinko/ https://github.com/dangsunm

Summary

Computer Science graduate. Trying to enter and build a career in data science in earnest by gaining various experiences. Passionate in new IT technologies, Datazation, mobility and free knowledge. Previously had 1.5 years of working experience in multinational non-profit organizations for community facilitation and collaboration. Also long term volunteer in a non-profit movement that intends to spread free knowledge widely. Always strive to work passionately with an attitude of embracing and learning.

Education

York University / Hons. BSc. Computer Science

September 2016 - February 2021, Toronto, ON, Canada

King City Secondary School / Ontario. Scholar

September 2012 - June 2016, King City, ON, Canada

Skills

Tools

- Web-development, Data Analysis:
 - o HTML, JSP, JS, CSS, Java,
 - Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, QueryDSL
 - SQL(MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, Postgresql, H2)
 - Python(Numpy, Pandas)
- Software/Office Tools:
 - Windows, MacOS
 - MS Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
 - o Google Docs
 - Slack, Asana, MS Teams 등 다양한 협업 소프트웨어 경험.

Soft Skills

- Community Facilitation
- Project planning
- Event organization
- Online-Community Governance, Trust and Safety,
- Translation (English <-> Korean)

Language

- 한국어 Korean Native
- English Professional

Projects during undergraduate:

- Software Design
 - o Project: "제목"

- Building E-Commerce Systems
 - o Project: "Building E-commerce website"
- Human-Computer Interaction
 - Project: "Evaluating the Speed and Efficiency of Virtual Keyboards on Mobile Devices by Their Display Size"

Work Experience

Wlkimedia Foundation/ Freelance Translator

July 2022 - Present

Providing translation services for Wikimedia Foundation between English and Korean.

- Example: "Sound Of All Human Knowledge" contest website: https://soundlogo.wikimedia.org/ko/?noredirect=ko-KR

Wikimedia Foundation/ Facilitator, Movement Strategy and Governance June 2021-June 2022, Remote

Served as community facilitator at Movement Strategy and Governance team.

- Engaging deeply with the Wikimedia communities and affiliates in East Asia, specifically in the Korean community.
- Acting as a conduit for community ideas, questions, and comments for the projects.
- Translation services for Movement Strategy and Governance related sessions and materials.
- Drafting, translating, and distributing invitations to participate in the community outreach process.
- Planning and organizing the movement-strategy related community outreach across the Wikimedia movement. (Including Conversation hours)

Wlkimedia Foundation/ Facilitator, Trust and Safety

January 2021-June 2021, Remote

Served as community facilitator for the Universal Code of Conduct project.

 Communicate/interact with the Korean community and collect feedback related to Enforcement Guidelines of Universal Code of Conduct.

Voluntary Services

Wlkimedia Korea / Board Member

February 2022 - Current

Serving as a Board Member at Wikimedia Korea in a voluntary role.

- Support local communities such as Korean Wikipedia
- Promote Wikimedia projects in South Korea
- Organizing annual local conference (Attended ~50 to 100 each year)
- Support the Wiki-related events hosted by other organizations/companies (such as WikiGap Editathon hosted by Swedish government, Wikipedia Workshop in Library)

Korean Wikipedia / Administrator

April 2014 - Current

- Moderating the Korean Wikipedia project and community
- Resolving conflicts between community members, and handling cases following the policies and guidelines established by the community.

York Region Transit / Student Ambassador

September 2013 - June 2016, York Region, Ontario

- Volunteer work as student ambassador to promote public transport in the York Region for high school and local community.
- Feedback on improvements in public transportation

Conference

Global

- Wikimania 2020 (Stockholm, Sweden; Global scholarship),
- Wikimania 2021 (Remote; WMF representative)
- Wikimania 2022 (Remote)
- **Wikimedia ESEAP Conference** 2022 (Sydney, Australia; WMKR representative)

Local

- WikiConference Seoul 2014, 2020, 2021, 2022